Ester Beltrami

About me

Email: beltrami.ester@gmail.com

LinkedIn: esterbeltrami
GitHub: estyxx

I am a passionate full-stack developer with a degree in Computer Science and over 4+ years of experience building websites and products using **Django**, **PostgreSQL**, **React** and **REST/GraphQL** as my favourite tech stack.

In my free time, I also love to attend and help organize Python conferences such as PyCon Italy and contribute to open-source projects.

I also have experience working with Aglie, Scrum, CI/CD, AWS, NoSQL and more.

Experience

Digitalis - Dec 2019 - Today

Full Stack Web Developer in London

At Digitalis I used to work on a web application to allow extraction of information from the web, get notified if anything chances on social media such as Twitter/Facebook and more tools allowing our internal teams to work more effectively.

My primary role was to work on the **microservices**-based backend built using **Django** and **DRF** by either building new services or improving existing ones. I also took some of the **DevOps** responsibility of the project by implementing a **CI** infrastructure using Jenkins to test and deploy our services to **AWS** on **ElasticBeanstalk**. Occasionaly, I also helped with the **React** frontend with new features and bug fixing.

OT Consulting - May 2016 - Nov 2019

Full Stack Web Developer in Reggio Emilia, Italy

At OT Consulting I used to be a consultant for Max Mara, an international fashion company, helping them develop internal tools for inventory management for their warehouse, support the new Italian's electronic invoice and more.

My responsibilities consisted of building new tools that are the technical solution for their needs, maintain and offer support for their existing processes and offer training to the new junior developers on Python and other technologies.

The tech stack we used for our tools was Python for backend and Javascript with AngularJS for the frontend.

Open source

I am working on the new website for our conference **PyCon Italy** (https://pycon.it/) by helping building it from scratch both the new backend and frontend using technologies such as **Django**, **GraphQL** and **NextJS**.

I also try to give back to the open-source community by contributing and helping projects I use and love, such as Poetry and more.

Education

2009 - 2016 Degree from the Department of Physical, Computer Science and Mathematics in the Computer Science Degree
Course

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, Italy with 100/110 evaluation

 2009 Diploma of Accountant, Commercial Expert and Programmer I.T.C.G. Institute "Luigi Einaudi" of Correggio RE, Italy